Preliminary Guide to the Graphic Design Student Projects Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Graphic Design Student Projects Collection
1974-1993
AOB 28
Yale University Arts Library
3
(3 boxes)
Collection of projects completed by graduate students in classes of the Yale School of Art Graphic Design Program. Items include projects produced for classes taught by Bradbury Thompson, Paul Rand, and Alvin Eisenman.
Yale University. School of Art. Graphic Design Program
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the School of Art.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of projects completed by graduate students in classes of the Yale School of Art Graphic Design Program. Items include projects produced for classes taught by Bradbury Thompson, Paul Rand, and Alvin Eisenman.
Arrangement
Preliminarily arranged by type of project: Binding Design Projects; Book Design Projects; Type Design Projects.
Graphic design (Typography); Book design
- Box Listing
  - Binding Design Projects
    - Kinneret, 1986; Hollander, John, 1929-2013 (Box 1)
  - Book Design Projects
    - Brad Books, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      These books were designed for classes taught by Bradbury Thompson.
    - Brad Books (continued), 1984 1993 undated (Box 2)
    - Design and the Play Instinct by Paul Rand, 1979-1980 1982 undated (Box 2)
      These student projects are from classes taught by Paul Rand.
    - Excerpts from Synchronization of Senses by Sergei Eisenstein, 1974 (Box 2)
    - On Plastic Art by Ozenfant and Jeanneret, 1975 (Box 3)
    - On the Plastic in Art by Ozenfant and Jeanneret, 1980-1984 undated (Box 3)
  - Type Design Projects
    - Typefaces project, 1983 (Box 3)
      These student projects are from classes taught by Alvin Eisenman.